<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vikram Jadhav</title>
    <link>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vikram Jadhav</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linked List implementation in Python</title>
      <link>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-05-28-python-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-05-28-python-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>In computer science Linked list is a data structure contains sequence of nodes where each node points to the next node in the sequence. We can also say the node stores a reference to the next node.
 Linked List is a very popular data structure as it is very flexible and can be used to implement other abstract data types such as Stack, Queue, Tree and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Copy and Deepcopy</title>
      <link>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-05-23-python-deepcopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-05-23-python-deepcopy/</guid>
      <description>Python&amp;rsquo;s Shallow and Deepcopy Python&amp;rsquo;s integer, float, boolean, string and tuple are immutable, means once assigned value to a variable it&amp;rsquo;s value can not be changed.
let&amp;rsquo;s take a simple example
number1 = 10 number2 = number1  In the above example as you can see we copied the reference of number1 and assigned it to the number2. let&amp;rsquo;s check if it is true!
number1 = 10 print id(number1) # 54032216 number2 = number1 print id(number2) # 54032216  So let&amp;rsquo;s re-assign the value of number1 to 20, then it should change the value of number2 right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript: How to detect online status in browser</title>
      <link>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-01-22-javascript-detect-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-01-22-javascript-detect-online/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we need to check whether the user is online. In today&amp;rsquo;s world, more than billion people are online, but not everyone has a better internet connection; so there is a nice feature in modern browsers that we can cache the data in the browser&amp;rsquo;s local storage so next time the user visits, there is no need to download the data again.
 The browsers provide navigator property that will help us to find the online status of the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: The difference between &#39;==&#39; and &#39;is&#39;</title>
      <link>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-01-01-diff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-01-01-diff/</guid>
      <description>For a beginner, the is operator may seem like as the == operator but actually, those are not same.
Basic principle of object creation Computer Science  An object can be a variable, a data structure, a function or a method when defined, new memory location is created and a value assigned to it.
 So in the context of python, when a new variable, dict, list is defined, new memory location is created and a value is assigned to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: Tuple Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-01-01-python-tuples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codingwithvikram.surge.sh/post/2017-01-01-python-tuples/</guid>
      <description>Tuple represents one of the three currently implemented sequence data types along with lists and ranges.
Tuples are used to group any number of items into a single compound value regardless if their type
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; the_tuple = (&#39;names&#39;, 55, False, &#39;youtube&#39;) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; type (the_tuple) tuple  We can extract elements from the tuple using the index operator
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; the_tuple[1] 55  The index must be a valid number and withing the range of the tuple</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>